# Hendrik Fick Renaldo Potgieter

Email: Email me

Contact: 066 098 0801

Website: My Website

Github: Github Account

LinkedIn: Linkedin Profile

Address: Gauteng, South Africa

## 1. PERSONAL INFORMATION

Surname: Potgieter

Name: Hendrik Fick Renaldo

Languages: Afrikaans and English

Driver's License: Code B

### 2. PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an independent, hardworking and creative individual who is also reliable and has developed a responsible and ethical approach to the tasks that I undertake or any given situation I am placed in. I am excellent at working and communicating in a team. I believe in integrity and strong moral values and that an individual should strive to be successful not only in their career but also in their personal life. I also believe that everything you put your energy into, you can be successful in it if you do it with a positive mindset and with hard work.

### 3. CAREER OR GOAL OBJECTIVE

I am looking for an opportunity to grow and learn in my field of study. I understand that there is still much to learn, and I am willing and eager to learn new skills. I like to solve complex problems and I try to solve them in a creative, efficient way. When a problem grips me, I push myself to find a solution and I will not be satisfied until it is resolved. I am a hardworking, focused and disciplined individual with a big amount of willpower. I have the correct amount of computer, communication and teamwork skills to be appointed to this position.



## 4. ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

1. Tertiary Education:

University:	North-West University, Potchefstroom Campus, (South Africa) Student Number: 29971349
Post Graduate Degree:	Bachelor of Science Honours in Computer Science and Information Technology (with distinction). (2021).
Graduate Degree:	Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (with distinction). (2018 – 2020).

2. Secondary Education

High School:	High School Sentraal, Free State (2013 – 2017)
Highest Education:	Matriculated
Subjects passed:	Afrikaans - 69% English - 76% Mathematics - 66% Life Orientation - 78% Engineering graphics and Design - Distinction - 84% Information Technology - 73% Physical Sciences - 73%

## 5. LIFE EXPERIENCE

### 1. SPORT

University:

- De Wilgers (Pukke) Second team hockey 2018
- De Wilgers (Pukke) First year's football team 2018
- De Wilgers (Pukke) Second team hockey 2019

## High School:

- Athletics: Pole vault (Free State Team 2014)
- Athletics: Pole vault (Free State Team 2016)

### 2. CULTURE

## University:

- SJCG Recycling Sub-Committee 2018
- Hostel: Culture Committee 2018
- Hostel: Enkelsêr 2018
- Hostel: Canvas 2018
- Hostel: Binglesêr 2018
- Hostel: Binglesër 2019
- Hostel: Culture Committee 2019
- Hostel: Canvas 2019
- Hostel: Culture Committee 2020
- Hostel: Canvas 2020
- Hostel: Canvas 2021

#### 3. ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

2016:

• SAICE Bridge Building Competition.

2017:

• SAICE Bridge Building Competition.

2018:

• North-West University academic merit bursary.

2019:

- Golden Key International Honour Society Member.
- Academic Top 10 in De Wilgers Manskoshuis (1st).
- North-West University academic merit bursary.

2020:

• North-West University academic merit bursary.

### 6. INTEREST AND HOBBIES

Music: I do enjoy listening to music, but I also play instruments such as the

guitar. **Reading:** I enjoy reading and I try to read when I have time.

**Sport:** I enjoy watching sport, but also playing it casually. I enjoy playing any form of team sport for my hostel.

**Welding:** I participated in my residence's JOOL/RAG building team where I learned a lot and enjoyed welding.

**Woodworking:** I enjoy working with wood and building furniture for my family and friends.

## 7. Career Highlights

## 1. Neptune NCP Chlorchem South Africa project (2021):

Played an important role in developing a software solution, using Neptune Software, to support business processes crucial to NCP. This was achieved by integrating various SAP functions through different API calls as well as important cross-platform technologies such as Cordova. Physical devices were also integrated by making use of independent, custom-built, server scripts, built in Neptune, to interface with the different devices.

#### 2. Solution Developer at Linxas (2022):

Started a full-time position as a solution developer at Linxas where I have gained experience with a variety of different programming languages and frameworks. These programming languages and frameworks include Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ionic Angular, Angular, GuiXT, and C#. A highlight of my position to date is a Fullstack Web Application written in lonic Angular which one of our clients use to pull global reports for their business. This solution consists of an Ionic Angular front-end web application and an accompanying Node.js Express REST API that pulls information from a MySQL database that is hosted on a cloud server.

#### 3. Subcontracted Software Developer at PicknPay (2022):

Started a position at Pick n Pay as a JavaScript developer as well as a Neptune-Software developer. I play a critical role in developing AJAX calls that pull information directly from SAP functions. I also develop native JavaScript functions that interface with various SAP functions and native libraries.

#### 3. Graduate Software Developer at Nile.ag (2023):

Started a position as a Golang developer at Nile.ag.

#### 8. WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Assistant

Company: North-West University, Potchefstroom Campus, North West, South Africa. Date: February 2019 - June 2019. – Assisting and marking first year's Python programming practical assignments and tests.

#### Internship

Company: Movation (Pty) Ltd., E.P Malan Street, Pomona AH, Kempton Park, Gauteng, South Africa. Date: Started 18 June 2019 – 21 June 2019. – Practical workweek to gain experience in the workplace.

## **Part-time Developer**

Company: Linx/AS, Unit 3, Verona Office Park Cnr Malibongwe &, MacArthur Ave, Robindale, Randburg, 2194. Date started 18 November 2019 – 14 August 2020. – Developed a mobile front-end and accompanying back-end.

#### **Assistant**

Company: North-West University, Potchefstroom Campus, North West, South Africa. Date: Started February 2021 - June 2021. – Assisting and marking final year's Artificial Intelligence (AI) practical assignments and tests.

#### **Assistant**

Company: North-West University, Potchefstroom Campus, North West, South Africa. Date: Started February 2021 - June 2021. – Assisting and marking second year's C# programming practical assignments and tests.

#### **Assistant**

Company: North-West University, Potchefstroom Campus, North West, South Africa. Date: Started August 2021 - December 2021. – Assistant to Professor Rollien Goede for a computer science module: Data Structures.

## **Solutions Developer**

Company: Linx/AS, Unit 3, Verona Office Park Cnr Malibongwe &, MacArthur Ave, Robindale, Randburg, 2194. Date started January 2022 - February 2023. - Solutions developer working in various languages and frameworks such as Java, Node.js (REST-API), Angular, Ionic and C#

#### 9. REFERENCES:

**Employer:** Dr Dirk Snyman; North-West University; Potchefstroom. 082

367 3778

**Employer:** Mr Kenneth Jackson; Movation (Pty) Ltd.; Kempton Park.

ken.jackson@movation.co.za

**Employer:** Mr Werner Simpson; Linx-AS LLC. Randburg; 083

495 3955

Employer: Mr Zander Boonzaaeir; North-West University; Potchefstroom. 076

627 9479

**Employer:** Ms Rolien Goede; North-West University; Potchefstroom. 018